<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Home</title>
    <link>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building Statistical Models in R Linear Regression</title>
      <link>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Three hundred and forty-eight years, six months, and nineteen days ago to-day, the Parisians awoke to the sound of all the bells in the triple circuit of the city, the university, and the town ringing a full peal.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter VI: Esmeralda</title>
      <link>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>We are delighted to be able to inform the reader, that during the whole of this scene, Gringoire and his piece had stood firm. His actors, spurred on by him, had not ceased to spout his comedy, and he had not ceased to listen to it. He had made up his mind about the tumult, and was determined to proceed to the end, not giving up the hope of a return of attention on the part of the public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter IV: Master Jacques Coppenole</title>
      <link>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/post/project-41/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/post/project-41/</guid>
      <description>blah blah 4th project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter II: Pierre Gringoire</title>
      <link>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Nevertheless, as be harangued them, the satisfaction and admiration unanimously excited by his costume were dissipated by his words; and when he reached that untoward conclusion: “As soon as his illustrious eminence, the cardinal, arrives, we will begin,” his voice was drowned in a thunder of hooting.
“Begin instantly! The mystery! the mystery immediately!” shrieked the people. And above all the voices, that of Johannes de Molendino was audible, piercing the uproar like the fife’s derisive serenade: “Commence instantly!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/about/</guid>
      <description>Illustration from Victor Hugo et son temps (1881)   The Hunchback of Notre-Dame (French: Notre-Dame de Paris) is a French Romantic/Gothic novel by Victor Hugo, published in 1831. The original French title refers to Notre Dame Cathedral, on which the story is centered. English translator Frederic Shoberl named the novel The Hunchback of Notre Dame in 1833 because at the time, Gothic novels were more popular than Romance novels in England.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Follow me on these social media platforms:
   Platform URL     Kaggle: https://www.kaggle.com/arielfelices   Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ariel-felices-531202212/   Github: https://github.com/A-C-A-F    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
