<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SQL on Home</title>
    <link>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/sql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SQL on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/sql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SQL Data Aggregation</title>
      <link>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/sql/sql-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/sql/sql-1/</guid>
      <description>This project is for people who are interested in manipulating data in a database, that is, retrieving data from a database to get summaries and insights using SQL.
Below are the key objectives of this project:  Retrieve data as summaries from tables of a database using SQL aggregate functions Understand how to set conditions on the result set of a query using the HAVING clause  Below is the summary of the tasks performed in this project:  Task 1: INTRODUCTION Task 2: COUNT() Task 3: SELECT DISTINCT &amp;amp; GROUP BY Task 4: HAVING Task 5: SUM() Task 6: MIN() &amp;amp; MAX() Task 7: AVG() Task 8: ROUND  You can find the source data and my codes in my Project&amp;rsquo;s GitHub Repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Joins</title>
      <link>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/sql/sql-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/sql/sql-2/</guid>
      <description>This project is for people who are interested in manipulating data in a database, that is, retrieving data from a database to get summaries and insights using SQL.
Below are the key objectives of this project:  Retrieve desired result set using the different types of joins in SQL Join more than two tables in a database using SQL Joins  Below is the summary of the tasks performed in this project:  Task 1: Getting Started: Understand concepts of SQL Joins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Subqueries</title>
      <link>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/sql/sql-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/sql/sql-3/</guid>
      <description>This project is for people who are interested in manipulating data in a database, that is, retrieving data from a database to get summaries and insights using SQL.
Below are the key objectives of this project:  Use subqueries in the WHERE clause Use subqueries in the FROM clause Use subqueries in the SELECT clause  Below is the summary of the tasks performed in this project:  Task 1: Getting Started: Retrieve data from tables in the employees database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Data Definition and Manipulation</title>
      <link>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/sql/sql-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/sql/sql-4/</guid>
      <description>This project is for people who are interested in creating and manipulating data in a database, that is, retrieving data from a database to get summaries and insights using SQL.
Below are the key objectives of this project:  Using SQL data definition statements for various data definition tasks such as creating a database, tables. Using SQL data manipulation statements for various data manipulation tasks such as updating records of a table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL String Functions</title>
      <link>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/sql/sql-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/sql/sql-5/</guid>
      <description>This project is for people who are interested in creating and manipulating data in a database, that is, retrieving data from a database to get summaries and insights using SQL.
Below are the key objectives of this project:  Understand how string functions work and when to use them Clean data using different string functions Manipulate data using SQL SELECT statements together with string functions  Below is the summary of the tasks performed in this project:  Task 1: Create and Retrieve additional tables Task 2: LENGTH, LEFT, RIGHT Task 3: UPPER &amp;amp; LOWER Task 4: REPLACE Task 5: TRIM, RTRIM, LTRIM Task 6: Concatenation Task 7: SUBSTRING Task 8: String Aggregation Task 9: COALESCE  Link to GitHub Repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL CASE Statements</title>
      <link>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/sql/sql-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/sql/sql-6/</guid>
      <description>This project is for people who are interested in writing conditional statements and manipulating data in a database, that is retrieving data from a database to get insights using SQL.
Below are the key objectives of this project:  Understand the function of CASE statements in SQL Write simple CASE statements Write complex CASE statements  Below is the summary of the tasks performed in this project:  Task 1: The SQL CASE statement Task 2: Adding multiple conditions to a CASE statement Task 3: The CASE Statement and Aggregate Functions Task 4: The CASE Statement and SQL Joins Task 5: The CASE Statement together with Aggregate Functions and Joins Task 6: Transposing data using the CASE clause  Link to GitHub Repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Date Time Functions</title>
      <link>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/sql/sql-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a-c-a-f.github.io/Ariel_Portfolio/sql/sql-7/</guid>
      <description>This project is for people who are interested in writing conditional statements and manipulating data in a database, that is retrieving data from a database to get insights using SQL.
Below are the key objectives of this project:  Understand how SQL Date Time functions works and when to use them Manipulate date-like data using different Date Time functions Manipulate data in tables using SQL SELECT statements together with Date Time functions  Below is the summary of the tasks performed in this project:  Task 1:	Retrieve data from tables in the employees database Task 2:	Use the CURRENT_DATE, CURRENT_TIME &amp;amp; CURRENT_TIMESTAMP functions to retrieve data Task 3:	Use the AGE function to retrieve data from tables in the employees database Task 4:	Use the AGE function in more real-life applications Task 5:	Use the EXTRACT function to retrieve data from tables in the employees database Task 6:	Use the EXTRACT function in more real-life applications Task 7:	Use the TO_CHAR function to convert date to strings Task 8:	Use the TO_DATE function to convert strings to date  Link to GitHub Repository.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
